<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://joshling1919.github.io/rss-feed/index.html</id>
    <title>rss feed</title>
    <updated>2022-07-03T00:21:27.548Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://joshling1919.github.io/rss-feed/index.html"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://joshling1919.github.io/rss-feed/feed.atom"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Putting Ideas into Words]]></title>
        <id>http://www.paulgraham.com/words.html</id>
        <link href="http://www.paulgraham.com/words.html"/>
        <updated>2022-06-18T00:17:58.027Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[February 2022
Writing about something, even something you know well, usually shows
you that you didn't know it as well as you thought. Putting ideas
into words is a severe test. The first words you choose are usually
wrong; you have to rewrite sentences over and over  to
get them exactly right. And your ideas won't just be imprecise, but
incomplete too. Half the ideas that end up in an essay will be ones
you thought of while you were writing it. Indeed, that's why I write
them.
Once you publish something, the convention is that whatever you
wrote was what you thought before you wrote it. These were your
ideas, and now you've expressed them. But you know this isn't true.
You know that putting your ideas into words changed them. And not
just the ideas you published. Presumably there were oth…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Paul Graham: Essays</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is There Such a Thing as Good Taste?]]></title>
        <id>http://www.paulgraham.com/goodtaste.html</id>
        <link href="http://www.paulgraham.com/goodtaste.html"/>
        <updated>2022-06-16T00:16:30.686Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[November 2021
(This essay is derived from a talk at the Cambridge Union.)
When I was a kid, I'd have said there wasn't. My father told me so.
Some people like some things, and other people like other things,
and who's to say who's right?
It seemed so obvious that there was no such thing as good taste
that it was only through indirect evidence that I realized my father
was wrong. And that's what I'm going to give you here: a proof by
reductio ad absurdum. If we start from the premise that there's no
such thing as good taste, we end up with conclusions that are
obviously false, and therefore the premise must be wrong.
We'd better start by saying what good taste is. There's a narrow
sense in which it refers to aesthetic judgements and a broader one
in which it refers to preferences of any kin…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Paul Graham: Essays</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weird Languages]]></title>
        <id>http://www.paulgraham.com/weird.html</id>
        <link href="http://www.paulgraham.com/weird.html"/>
        <updated>2022-06-16T00:16:30.625Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[August 2021
When people say that in their experience all programming languages
are basically equivalent, they're making a statement not about
languages but about the kind of programming they've done.
99.5% of programming consists of gluing together calls to library
functions. All popular languages are equally good at this. So one
can easily spend one's whole career operating in the intersection
of popular programming languages.
But the other .5% of programming is disproportionately interesting.
If you want to learn what it consists of, the weirdness of weird
languages is a good clue to follow.
Weird languages aren't weird by accident. Not the good ones, at
least. The weirdness of the good ones usually implies the existence
of some form of programming that's not just the usual gluing togeth…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Paul Graham: Essays</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Beyond Smart]]></title>
        <id>http://www.paulgraham.com/smart.html</id>
        <link href="http://www.paulgraham.com/smart.html"/>
        <updated>2022-06-16T00:16:30.588Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[October 2021
If you asked people what was special about Einstein, most would say
that he was really smart. Even the ones who tried to give you a
more sophisticated-sounding answer would probably think this first.
Till a few years ago I would have given the same answer myself. But
that wasn't what was special about Einstein. What was special about
him was that he had important new ideas. Being very smart was a
necessary precondition for having those ideas, but the two are not
identical.
It may seem a hair-splitting distinction to point out that intelligence
and its consequences are not identical, but it isn't. There's a big
gap between them. Anyone who's spent time around universities and
research labs knows how big. There are a lot of genuinely smart
people who don't achieve very much.
I g…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Paul Graham: Essays</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Heresy]]></title>
        <id>http://www.paulgraham.com/heresy.html</id>
        <link href="http://www.paulgraham.com/heresy.html"/>
        <updated>2022-06-13T00:19:33.698Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[April 2022
One of the most surprising things I've witnessed in my lifetime is
the rebirth of the concept of heresy.
In his excellent biography of Newton, Richard Westfall writes about the
moment when he was elected a fellow of Trinity College:

  Supported comfortably, Newton was free to devote himself wholly
  to whatever he chose. To remain on, he had only to avoid the three
  unforgivable sins: crime, heresy, and marriage.
  [1]

The first time I read that, in the 1990s, it sounded amusingly
medieval. How strange, to have to avoid committing heresy. But when
I reread it 20 years later it sounded like a description of
contemporary employment.
There are an ever-increasing number of opinions you can be fired
for. Those doing the firing don't use the word "heresy" to describe
them, but stru…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Paul Graham: Essays</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>