<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://joshling1919.github.io/rss-feed/index.html</id>
    <title>rss feed</title>
    <updated>2022-04-14T00:17:48.170Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.14.4</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://joshling1919.github.io/rss-feed/index.html"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://joshling1919.github.io/rss-feed/feed.atom"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Heresy]]></title>
        <id>http://www.paulgraham.com/heresy.html</id>
        <link href="http://www.paulgraham.com/heresy.html"/>
        <updated>2022-04-12T00:15:19.817Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[April 2022
One of the most surprising things I've witnessed in my lifetime is
the rebirth of the concept of heresy.
In his excellent biography of Newton, Richard Westfall writes about the
moment when he was elected a fellow of Trinity College:

  Supported comfortably, Newton was free to devote himself wholly
  to whatever he chose. To remain on, he had only to avoid the three
  unforgivable sins: crime, heresy, and marriage.
  [1]

The first time I read that, in the 1990s, it sounded amusingly
medieval. How strange, to have to avoid committing heresy. But when
I reread it 20 years later it sounded like a description of
contemporary employment.
There are an ever-increasing number of opinions you can be fired
for. Those doing the firing don't use the word "heresy" to describe
them, but stru…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Paul Graham: Essays</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Beautiful News book US Edition – out this week]]></title>
        <id>https://informationisbeautiful.net/?p=8889</id>
        <link href="https://informationisbeautiful.net/2022/beautiful-news-book-us-edition-out-this-week/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-29T20:16:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[200+ hand-crafted infographics and visualisations, surfacing positive trends, uplifting stats and creative solutions to the world’s problems – in handy, multi-coloured book form. The book is also full of fresh new infographic primers and visualisations which delve deeper into certain key topics. These are designed to better arm you with context and understanding when doom-scrolling headlines and news stories about climate, or […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David McCandless</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ukraine-Russian War Infographics & Data Visuals]]></title>
        <id>https://informationisbeautiful.net/?p=8946</id>
        <link href="https://informationisbeautiful.net/2022/ukraine-russian-war-infographics-data-visuals/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-26T13:40:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A collection of visualisations, maps and primers from around the web. We’ll keep this list updated. » Total Refugees from Ukraine, compared to other countries [Flowing Data] » Visualising the $13.6 billion US spend on Ukraine [New York Times] » Russian Oil – who imports it? Who’s Most Dependent on it? [Information is Beautiful] » […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David McCandless</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Putting Ideas into Words]]></title>
        <id>http://www.paulgraham.com/words.html</id>
        <link href="http://www.paulgraham.com/words.html"/>
        <updated>2022-03-17T00:13:50.253Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[February 2022
Writing about something, even something you know well, usually shows
you that you didn't know it as well as you thought. Putting ideas
into words is a severe test. The first words you choose are usually
wrong; you have to rewrite sentences over and over  to
get them exactly right. And your ideas won't just be imprecise, but
incomplete too. Half the ideas that end up in an essay will be ones
you thought of while you were writing it. Indeed, that's why I write
them.
Once you publish something, the convention is that whatever you
wrote was what you thought before you wrote it. These were your
ideas, and now you've expressed them. But you know this isn't true.
You know that putting your ideas into words changed them. And not
just the ideas you published. Presumably there were oth…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Paul Graham: Essays</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>